#### **Sarvottam Dave**

H.N.101 Gautam Nagar Dewas-M.P.455001 Cell No.-(7509631040) Email ID:- sarvottam29engineer@gmail.com

<u>Professional Summary</u> -Having 7 years of experience in Telecom industry with extensive exposure on RF, Copper and Fiber with handling trouble tickets and delivery of circuits within SLA. Reputation for dedicated teamwork, strong work ethic, and commitment to delivering results. Capacity to do work for meeting deadlines. Knowledge of MS word, Excel, Accesses & PowerPoint presentation

\_\_\_\_\_

# **Technical Skills-**

- Knowledge of CCNA (networking).
- Understanding of OSI,TCP-IP model
- Routing & Switching Concept.
- Cisco & Huawei Router configuration
- Basic knowledge of Routing protocols.(RIP,BGP,OSPF,IGRP,EIGRP)
- Cisco & Huawei Router configuration
- Network Monitoring and Tracking
- Network Troubleshooting
- Technical Support
- Solution/LEPM/IB2B/ECRM,PUTTY/RDP)
- PDH, SDH/, RF, Copper, Fiber Media

**WORK HISTORY** 

20 Febuary 2023 to Till Date Bharti Airtel Project & Network Support Engineer, Ahmadabad Job Responsibilities-

- Responsible for Deployment work in PAN india for Emerging Enterprise Government other Customer, & Customer related issue We are Working Different- Different Projects & operations and End to End Link Delivered.
- Provide first level troubleshooting (FLT) for physical connectivity(Link Down, Packet Drop, Link Flapping, Website accessibility, Low Bandwidth, Slow Browsing, Reachability issues Hub & Spoke.
- Planning/Implementation/ Monitoring new Projects.
- Monitor all configured sites in NMS(Network Monitoring tool)
- Network monitoring, Network troubleshooting, Network testing & Network Optimization, Alarm notification.
- Configurations of Router like Cisco and Huawei Router
- Troubleshot complex multi-vendor network service provider issues
- Performed troubleshooting for Huawei, Cisco Routers.
- Assisted with implementation and support of network monitoring tools
- Provided complete end-to-end engineering and installation of route-based IP network solutions.

- Supervise and technical service during the engineering process including site survey, equipments hardware installation and software commissioning, data configuration and integration, swap activities
- Closing the ticket ID with the proper resolution method followed by engineer to troubleshoot the issue.
- Check and generate the Shift report, Daily call report, Monthly call report.
- LOC generate & Sign off at customer end and Upload in Data-Bas EPM(Enterprises Project Management tool)
- Hands-on experience on internal tools(IB2B/M6(Meta-Solv Solution/Eassy access/service now/LEPM/LEO/ECRM,PUTTY/RDP/Raise to RMA used to Cisco Portal)

#### 18 Feb.2022 to 16 August-2022

# BT Global Business Services -Pvt. Limited, Associate Engineer Gurgaon Job Responsibilities-

- Work under Fibre and Network Delivery(FND) logical recording which is pre- commissioning team, CSS
  database tool responsible for E-recording of logical records of DSLAMs and PCB, cabinets are installed in
  between networks.
- Responsible for the building the network through the CSS by analyzing the certified information of Cabinet images
- Checking the connection end to end rectifying the defaults and ensuring that .route has no defaults.
- Managing Network mapping which includes planning, recording and performing connectivity for copper and fibre network including network for ISP cabinets.
- Responsible for to make sure that cabinets are available for DSLAMs for providing effective broadband connectivity to customers.
- To confirm connectivity, routing details are provide accurate information to Field engineers, Internal Teams.
- Resolving and recording to Data integrity.issues of the network and fibre routes directly to hub sites for the core Network, FTTC/FTTP/FTTX.
- Planning of sites on tool responsible PIPER and generating field work for engineers.
- Responsible for the building the network through the CSS by analyzing the certified information of Cabinet images.
- Check and generate the Shift report, Daily report, Monthly Task report
- Following proper Escalation Matrix.
- Escalation of Customer technical issues to next level of Resolution desk.
- Hands-on experience on internal tools(SI/CSS/COSMOSS/Share-point-Tracker/Tie Tracker/Lums/Piper/WFMT/DSLAM/Issue-Register/Srims/Formwise/DI-Tracker/Scheme/Down-time formwise/Kronos.
- Working in 24\*7 environment.

# 1 Sep.2018 to 16 Febuary 2022 Bharti Airtel Network Engineer Gurgaon Job Responsibilities-

- Responsible for Project Coordinator & Network Support Engineer Customer access issue & Deployment work in PAN india for PNB, Maruti Suzuki , Suzuki - Motor cycle & Hero Motor Corporation Ltd Projects & operations and End to End Link Delivered.
- Handling operation IP/MPLS network infrastructure with multiple circuits of AIRTEL
- Managed 30-40 ticket on daily basis and updated internal customers regarding open tickets and status of resolutions

- Troubleshooting of MPLS,BGP, QoS, LAN, Router, RF & copper/Fibre media.
- Established coordination between NOC, ENOC, IWAN, Media team and Field Engineer for resolving issue within TAT.
- Performed Network testing for RF, Copper, Fibre, Transmission with Testing team & NOC team.
- Supervise and technical service during engineering process including site survey, equipment hardware installation and software commissioning, data configuration and integration, swap activities
- Planning/Implementation/ Monitoring new Projects
- Monitor all configured sites in NMS(Network Monitoring tool) Network monitoring, Network troubleshooting, Network testing & Network
- Check and generate Shift report, Daily call report, Monthly call report.
- Created graphical reports to visualize network performance and uptime to management members
- Closed first-time tickets quickly and met resolution volume requirements
- Scheduled infrastructure upgrades and software update rollouts around high traffic times to maintain network availability
- Exceeded SLA standards for response times and problem resolution
- Installed fiber, ethernet, and console cabling in climate-controlled NOC
- Established positive working relationships with users to quickly resolve problems
- Coordinated with technical support, service provisioning and sales teams to deliver network services at or above SLA requirements
- Network monitoring, Network troubleshooting, Network testing & Network Optimization, Alarm notification.
- Closing the ticket ID with the proper resolution method followed by engineer to troubleshoot the issue.
- Check and generate the Shift report, Daily call report, Monthly call report.
- LOC generate & Sign off at customer end and Upload in Data-Bas EPM(Enterprises Project Management tool)
- Hands-on experience on internal tools(IB2B/M6(Meta-Solv Solution/Eassy access/service now/LEPM/ECRM,PUTTY/RDP/Raise to RMA used to Cisco Portal)

# 1 January 2018 to August-2018 Shiv Shakti Enterpeises Services Project Engineer Gurgaon Job Responsibilities-

- ECI-PROJECT, BG-20B&E,BG-20C,BG-30B&E,BG-64,NPT-1050,1200,Installation& Commissioning. For Airtel and Idea.
- Maintaining daily / weekly/ Monthly progress reports on all fronts of the project and reviewing it with project heads and contractors for the timely completion of the project.

# 31 January,2017 To 15 oct.2017 Reliance Communication Engineer MP&CG Job Responsibilities-

- Responsible for BSS and Transmission Engineer at Ujjain in Madhya-Pradesh Circle for all Technology (GSM-2G/3G) of Reliance Communication Network.
- Daily analysis of zero calls sectors & taking proper action to reduce count of zero calls sectors.
- Operation and Maintenance of ZTE (SDR/V2) indoor & outdoor BTS and Transmission NEC(PDH/SDH)
   Equipments..

- Cell site up gradation in terms of BTS expansion ,TRX addition, Sector addition Call testing Hand over testing Edge Implementation.
- Coordination with NMS team for uploading and visuality for MUX.
- Coordination with RF team for Optimization, Antenna Rectification, and Sector Swap rectification. EMF survey.
- VSWR measurement of RF cable Power calibration & Power measurement of BTS,correction of sector swap, Monitoring and Rectification of Faults in BTS & TRANSMISSION EQUIPMENT through OMCR Terminal.

# 1 oct 2015 to 31 oct-2016 MTS Pvt Ltd O&M Engineer Jaipur Job Responsibilities-

- Responsible for handling operation & maintenance of UBR(PRI, ILL).
- Regular communication with internal customers to meet production oriented requirements.
- supervise and technical service during the engineering process including site survey, equipments hardware installation and software commissioning, data configuration and integration, swap activities.
- Transmission Network maintenance.
- Plan/Support/Execute SW/HW upgrades in the Radio Network.
- Planning/ Implementation/ Monitoring new Projects.
- which includes monthly reports, activation reports, installation reports, PRI, lease line
- Installation of PRI & Leased line with testing & commissioning(SHYAM,RADWIN,MRO-TEK,CTC).
- Troubleshooting of Customer's MTS Project network, assist with upgrades and coordinate.

# **Education Qualification-**

#### Post Graduation:-

MSC.(Electronics) from Barkatullah University Bhopal (M.P.) with 72%

#### Graduation:-

B.Sc. (Electronics) from Barkatullah University Bhopal (M.P.) with 64%

# Academic:-

Higher Secondary (PCM) from M. P. Board, Bhopal with 65 % High School from M. P. Board, Bhopal with 60 %

# Awards and Achievements-

- Participated 51<sup>th</sup> DAE solid State Physics Symposium of BARC, Mumbai
- N.C.C 'B' Certificate.
- 6<sup>th</sup> Month training at Digital Integrator Pvt. Ltd., Indore

# **Personal Details-**

Father's name Shri Gajendra Kumar Dave

Date of birth 29June1988 Martial Status Married